Guide to the Cornell-Community Waste Management Advisory Committee records, 1996-2004.
Cornell-Community Waste Management Advisory Committee records,
- Series VII. Vendor Files
  - MedWaste Technologies, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    correspondence, laboratory reports, information about the company, KSI information
  - Norrie Engineering, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    letters, notes, KSI file with Norrie information
  - PEAT, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    file on PEAT from Guertin, response to Hirschhorn criteria questions, notes
  - Premier Medical Technology, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    correspondence, company information, laboratory reports
  - Pyros, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    notes, correspondence, mission statement, plasma gassification information
  - San-I-Pak, Inc. Autoclave-Enhanced, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    letter and request for information, fax describing CAT-1600 and other systems, responses to criteria questions
  - STI Chem-Clav, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    general process information, company information, letters, lab reports, correspondence
  - Tempico, Inc. Autoclave-Enhanced, 1993-1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    responses to RFI and criteria questions, customer reference sheets, correspondence
  - Vance IDS, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    company info, notes, letters concerning emissions test data
  - Waste Reduction 2 (I), 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    correspondence, analytical testing and waste processor specifications, notes
  - Waste Reduction 2 (II), 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Anderson 2000 Incinerator, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    proposal, correspondence
  - Antaeus Group Autoclave, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    correspondence, response to request for information
  - Bioconversion Technologies Chemical, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    informational booklet, correspondence
  - Biosterile Technology, Inc. Irradiation, 1994-1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    response to criteria questions, company information
  - Brinecell (Chemical), 1989-1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    reports, informational booklets
  - Consumat Incinerator, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    notes, company information, response to request for information, correspondence
  - HI Disposal Systems, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Pennram Incinerator, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    notes, company information, response to request for information, correspondence, binder with diagram on cover
  - Plasmarc, Inc. Off-Site, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sanitec, Inc. Microwave, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Simonds Manufacturing Incinerator, 1991-1997 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Sterile Technology Industries Chemical/Autoclave, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Svedala Industries Incinerator, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Thermal Waste Technologies Thermal, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Tuttnauer USA, Ltd. Autoclave, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - United McGill Autoclave, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Walsh Integrated Environmental Systems Inc., Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    one informational pamphlet
  - General Vendor Info., 1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    CCWMAC criteria for vendors, letter templates, mailing list, additional information
  - Exercise: Choose technologies for treatment of waste, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - CCWMAC Vendor Responses to Criteria Questions, 1997-08 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Mailing list
  - Hydroclave; Steam Sterilization; Norrie Engineering Inc., 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Correspondence and responses
  - Key to Vendor Technology Responses, 1997-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Hirschhorn technology assessment, drafts of vendor responses
- Series VIII. Waste Management Project Material
  - Analysis of Medical Waste at Cornell University from 1994-1996, 1997-05-21 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Medical waste reports, 1990-1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    National Technical Information Service, Waste Policy Institute, EPRI Healthcare Initiative
  - Newspaper clipppings and memos, 1996 -1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Site visits, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Malcolm Pirnie
  - Environmental Assessment Form, comments, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Waste Management Project Reports, Drafts, and Proposals, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Series IX. Waste Minimization and Management
  - Analysis of Medical Waste at Cornell University 1994-1996, 1997-05-21 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - CVM Waste Management Facility Proposed Action, 2000-10 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Environmental Assessment Form, comments, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Medical waste reports, 1990-1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Photo-documentation of CCVM Waste Minimization and Pollution Prevention Audit, 1997-08 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Site Visits, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - SUCF/Consultant scope of work (alternatives evaluation and DEIS prep), Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Vet waste management, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    correspondence, reviews, clippings, handwritten notes, more information about mad cow disease
  - Waste management project program study report, 1995-05 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Phase III: Mgmnt Plans for Incinerator, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Cornell CCVM PIW Treatment Study, correspondence, supporting documents
  - Waste management: quarterly/luncheon meetings, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    notes on SUCF, project schedule
  - DRAFT Development of the Proposed Action and Alternatives (Copy 1), 2000-09 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Comments in blue and red ink
  - CVM Waste Minimization and Pollution Control Assessment, 1998-06-22 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Comments in black ink
  - CVM Waste Management Retrofit Project, 1999-05 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Post-its and pencil markings
  - Tompkins County Environmental Directory, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - WPI Report, 1996, 1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
    Correspondence; handwritten notes on waste management
  - Documents Related to Interim Incinerator, SUCF, 1998-1999, undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
    Correspondence; handwritten notes; letters
- Series X. Working Groups
  - consultant choice working group, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Minutes, resume, correspondence
  - consultant choice working group additional documents, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - CCWG evironmental consultant notes, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    handwritten notes
  - CCWG notes and correspondence, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - CCWG notes and correspondence II, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    CUCVM Medical Waste Stream Analysis Report Revision 2.0 1997, DOH guidelines, related and supporting documents
  - Consultant Choice Working Group STV, 1992-1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    newspaper photocopies of other incinerator controversies, court case, STV background, handwritten notes
  - consultant liason working group, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Minutes, scope of work outline, correspondence, proposals
  - CLWG minutes and correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    minutes, correspondence, tech choice, information about plasma, site visit report, Hirschhorn proposal
  - CLWG Taylor Report, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    DM taylor comments on proposed methods of waste disposal at CCVM; correspondence
  - Final CLWG/Reivising Final Report, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    CLWG agendas, revisions, report
  - Consultants: Incinerator work proposals - CLWG, 1998-05-13 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Guertin and Hirschhorn
  - Follow-up Vendor Notes: CLWG (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Norrie Engineering
  - criteria working group, 1997-01-24-1997-06-16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    minutes, mission statement, correspondence, reports
  - Criteria Work Group folder 2, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    correspondence, reports, outline of criteria
  - Criteria working group screening and selection criteria, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    CCWMAC, SUCF and CVM
  - document and information management working group, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Readings to brief CCWMAC, minutes, letters, reports, data, correspondence, resume
  - documents committee, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    notes, organizational materials, tables of content, resources, 1996 bibliography
  - Microwave/Antaeus/Plasmarc/Autoclave Enhanced - Options Working Group, 1992-1997 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Options Working Group: assorted documents I, 1993-1997 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    correspondence, meeting minutes, informational documents about vendors and waste disposal methods, handwritten notes
  - Options Working Group: assorted documents II, 1993-1997 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - options working group: questionaire, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    questionaire and related documents
  - Options working group: Vendor Responses, 1995-1998 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Project evaluation: options working group, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Loucks selection, correspondence, project evaluation documents
  - Vendor visits: options working group, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    CCWMAC vendor visits to campus: notes
  - Hh: recommendations - waste minimization WG, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    waste minimization working group meeting agenda, recommended actions; and one document regarding the authoritarianism present in Cornell as an institution
  - Pojasek Report - WMWG; correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - waste mimization working group phase II, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    magazine photocopies, correspondence, handwritten notes, memoranda, Cornell College of Veterinary Medicine Waste Minimization and Pollution Prevention Report 1997, Pojasek Report - WMWG; correspondence
  - waste minimization working group, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    meeting notes and minutes, reports, informational resources
  - waste stream working group, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    minutes, Analysis of Medical Waste at Cornell University for the period 1994-1996, New York State Guidance for Regulated Medical Waste Treatment, Storage, Containment, Transport, and Disposal-December 1996, New York State guidelines and laws,
  - Waste stream working group 1995-1997, 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Waste stream working group 1997-1998, 1997-01-1998-08 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Animal and Medical Waste Treatment Study and Energy Evaluation Report 1 (August 1998); comments on analyses of waste stream (January 1997)
  - working group on the DEC permit process, 1996-12-20-1997-01-15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    minutes, correspondence
  - CAC: permit working group, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Creation of working groups and CCWMAC, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Working group minutes and documents, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Series XI. Substantive Materials
  - Dioxin and other pollutants: substantive materials, 1989-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    table of contents; publications, studies, news clippings
  - Dioxins: Health Council of the Netherlands, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    committee on the risk evaluation of substances: report
  - Evaluation techniques - risk assessment and environmental toxins: substantive materials, 1991-1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    table of contents; publications especially concerning risk assessment, reports, studies
  - Prions: substantive materials (Box 1, Folder 15)
    table of contents, publications,
  - Technical background, 1990-1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    table of contents; various publications, studies, reports, correspondence
  - Waste disposal options (I), 1988-1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    table of contents; various publications, studies, reports
  - Waste disposal options (II), 1988-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Waste reduction: substantive materials (I), 1988-1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    table of contents; publications, studies, news clippings, laws and regulations, plus vol. 14, no. 3. of Everyone's Backyard
  - Waste reduction: substantive materials (II), 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    publications by Environmental Working Group and Cascadia Consulting Group
  - Booklets about waste disposal in laboratories and hospitals, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    CDC, NIH, CGH Environmental Strategies, Inc.
  - Prions and Mad Cow Disease, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    email and article
  - DOH and Vendors, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    Salkin, DOH and vendor notes and information
  - NYS DOH regulatory documents, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    Information that NYS DOH requires of aplicants for permits for non-incineration/non-autoclave methods for disposing of regulated medical wastes. Includes an application form, DOH evaluation process, NYS public health law and codes.
  - Residues, 1997-12 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    charts of residue disposal options
  - Substantive Materials: dioxins and scientific steering committee, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Substantive Materials: Everyone's Backyard, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    Journal of the Grassroots Movement for Environmental Justice Center for Health, Environment and Justice
  - USDA - BSE and Cornell-NYS contract, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    bovine spongiform encephalopathies information, Agriculture and Markets Contract with CU and NYS
  - ICCR Meeting: Chlorinated Dioxin and Furan Formation, 1997-09-17 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Prions - Assorted Documents (II of II), 1996-2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Prions - Assorted Documents (I of II), 1993-1997 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    Analysis of BSE risk factors; animal health report